<?xml version="1.0"?>
<lessons>
    <lesson id="1" name="Introduction">
        <topic id="1">
            <title>What is PHP?</title>
            <content>
            <![CDATA[What is PHP?
                The term <b>PHP</b> stands for <b>Hypertext Preprocessor</b> (it was called Personal Home Page before) is 
                a widely-used open source general-purpose scripting language that is especially suited for 
                web development and can be embedded into HTML.
                <br/>PHP Language Structure
                <br/><b><i>Did you know?</i></b>
                <br/><br/>A PHP file also has the ability to contain HTML tags and include client-side scripts like JavaScript.
                In contrast to programming languages like C or Perl that require a lot of commands to 
                output HTML, PHP allows you to embed code directly into HTML pages. This means that you 
                can create dynamic web pages without needing to write lots of code. The PHP code is 
                enclosed within special start and end processing instructions <?php and ?>, which allow you 
                to easily switch in and out of PHP mode as needed.
                The second example provided demonstrates that HTML elements can be included within 
                PHP code by echoing them as strings. This allows for the integration of HTML tags, such as the 
                <p> tag, within PHP scripts. Furthermore, it is possible to create PHP files that do not contain any HTML tags at all. These 
                files, referred to as pure PHP files, solely consist of PHP code without any accompanying HTML markup.
            ]]>
            </content>
            <quiz>
                <question>
                    <text>What does PHP stand for?</text>
                    <options>
                        <option>Personal Home Page</option>
                        <option>Hypertext Preprocessor</option>
                        <option>Private Hosting Provider</option>
                    </options>
                    <answer>2</answer>
                </question>
                <question>
                    <text>PHP is a widely-used _____</text>
                    <options>
                        <option>Open-source language</option>
                        <option>Open-source script</option>
                        <option>Open-source general purpose scripting language</option>
                    </options>
                    <answer>3</answer>
                </question>
            </quiz>
        </topic>
    </lesson>
    <lesson id="2" name="Basic Syntax">
        <topic id="1">
            <title>PHP Tags</title>
            <content>
            <![CDATA[
                PHP parses a file by searching for specific opening and closing tags, <?php and ?>, 
                respectively. These tags indicate to PHP where to begin and end interpreting the code within 
                them. This parsing approach enables PHP to be embedded within various types of 
                documents since any content outside the opening and closing tags is disregarded by the 
                PHP parser. These type of tags are called delimiters. 
                Additionally, PHP provides a shorter alternative to the standard <?php echo statement, 
                known as <?=, which serves as a shorthand for the longer version.
            ]]>
            </content>
        </topic>
        <topic id="2">
            <title>PHP Comment Tag</title>
            <content>
            <![CDATA[
                A PHP comment tag is used in a single or multiple lines so that those inside the comment tag 
                would not be read and executed. It is used so that the programmers and the testers could 
                easily read and navigate the code for checking and improvements.
                There are ways to comment in PHP
                Single Line:
                Multiple Line:
            ]]>
            </content>
        </topic>
        <topic id="3">
            <title>Code Cohabitation</title>
            <content>
            <![CDATA[
                Your file consisted of three chunks of PHP code, each of which has printed some HTML text. 
                In this section, you'll create a script that has PHP code stuck in the middle of your HTML, and 
                you'll learn how these codes can peacefully coexist.
                1. Create a new HTML file in any text editor.
                2. Input the HTML below:
                3. Type the following PHP code:
                4. Add the closing tag of the HTML so that the document is valid:
                5. Save the file with the name “My First Cohabitation Tryout.php”.
                6. Put this file in the document root of the webserver.
                Remember!
                Choose PHP as your type of file, use ".php" as file extension name.
            ]]>
            </content>
        </topic>
    </lesson>
</lessons>